researchers have taken the tiny human
brains we can grow from stem cells
implanted a brain ship into them and
then implanted them into that brain
organoid in the head of a mouse let's
talk about it if you're not familiar
with our tiny human brain friends they
have a number of uses including doing
computation but I think the more
compelling work is in recovery from
brain injury there's been some research
in the use of them to recover from
strokes and it is promising but there's
a few things that need to be worked out
before we put them in humans when
growing a disembodied human brain the of
a body causes some issues it does end up
suffering from hypoxia after a fairly
short period of time there has been some
efforts to give them a circulatory
system and change their environment and
some have been able to keep them alive
for 10 months or more this makes them
particularly helpful for computation if
you're going to teach a tiny human brain
to do computation for you you want it to
remain alive for a while in the process
of learning how to make it do
computation it has been noticed that it
does better if it has something to do a
disembodied brain needs something to
stimulate it that's where using brain
computer interface comes into play you
can take that semi-mature brain organoid
attach it into a computer interface and
then implant it but continue to control
it after it's there doing so keeps the
cells activated it keeps it doing stuff
and it allows it to reconnect with the
other brain structures quite well brain
organoids are very invasive you can take
a human brain organoid put it in that
Mouse's brain and it'll make connections
not just with other neurons but all the
way down to the spinal cord they're so
good at doing this that you can even
take a decapitated fetal Mouse and it
can grow projections into the spinal
cord and even take control of those
muscles the specific reason they use
human brain organoids even with things
like mice and monkeys is because if it
is ever to be applicable to human
medicine they're going to have to work
with our brains there also seems to be
the issue that Mouse brains tend to
overgrow though if you were to implant
them into a damaged portion of the brain
it may become too large and cause
pressure on the brain and further damage
this one is really cool because it has
several applications it could be the
future of attaching brain computer
interfaces to your brain you may want to
make a copy of your brain a tiny one
attach to that interface and then
implant it preserving your structures
but time will tell on that this research
does have a hell of a lot of Promise
there's evidence that you can repair
portions of the brain that are damaged
that cause blindness or loss of other
Sensations like smell the reason that we
haven't made the jump to people just yet
and I wouldn't doubt that somebody's
asked a researcher to do it the reason
we haven't jump to people just yet is
because we need to make sure that we
have the best methods possible before we
make that jump if you do it too quickly
it can end up setting the field back
even decades when researchers first made
the jump to mice and rats and even
monkeys they didn't have the best
results they didn't know that there was
a period that they should wait before
implanting them and they didn't know
that the brain organoids did better
after they've been grown for a while
this is likely one of the major problems
was trying to Stem Cell seed a brain to
heal an injury it doesn't work the cells
don't survive knowing that they do
better when they've had electrical
stimulation knowing that they do even
better if they have that electrical
stimulation while still in the skull of
the patient there may be more advances
down the line and getting treatment too
early can mean the end of the patient
the end of the research and not having
the opportunity to have that treatment
down the line it is frustrating but
these are all things to consider I'm
excited for where this field is
going swarming in the culture